Hello, all my friends, and welcome to exercise number 78.
And this exercise, we are going to implement the QS data structure inside Java, so we open our intelligent
idea and we create a new Java class called Q.
OK, and this Q would be containing that data as a form of array.
So we have agreed that that the queue contains items insert, insert that inside and array.
For that I need to create in the same as the stack algorithm that we have created.
And before the same structure, I need to create a private intégré.
Here private and have a.
OK.
And it contains a fixed size that we are going to to insert it in the queue constructor and we we have
to make an event called front and end every year.
Okay.
And the same as the stack we have, you can use the capacity.
So if we are using that, if you need to get this tag capacity directly or we need to make a size function
later on.
So I will create that constructor here.
So the queue it took into the perimeter and size that we are going to see how how it will create a new
element in you array.
So here are our big wall to new array new into array of size size.
OK.
We are creating the new array exactly that we have created in the stack capacity equal to size if I
will not make it in the vacuum.
And you can remove it from the stack because we have a method called size, it will return the 2+1 for
this.
OK.
And we assigned the front equal to minus one and rear equal to minus one.
You see the difference between the queue structure and the stack, the stack it curves about the top.
But in the queue, it occurs about the front and the rear.
The front male.
OK, so let's start making the functions here.
I close the stack.
And start making their methods, you know, the first one.
It is often out of returning time, bullion is full and it took into the perimeter, nothing because
we are checking if there's a fall.
So if front, as we have said in the lectures before, their front equal equal to zero.
And.
Of time, I am printing dollar sign.
Yes.
If it is equal to size minus one, so I will create a variable called size here.
In size.
It's a global variable, and I will make this size equal to size.
OK.
In order to make it very simple here, it is equal to minus one than return true.
Otherwise, it will return false.
OK.
This is the first function to check if it is full or not.
Now let's create a method called is empty.
Also of type Boolean is empty it and checks.
If feront equal equal to minus one, then return true.
Otherwise else return false.
OK.
This is their method to check if there's empty or not.
Now I need from you to concentrate here with more complex methods by using that ink you.
So here the ink items.
Thank you.
It's called Ink Q.
Avoid in queue, it took to perimeter and element.
And it checks if.
If.
Is full
if full, so we will create this method later on.
OK, now it will print system that out the print and on the screen at the queue is false.
OK.
Otherwise, it will be adding the item successfully so else.
If from equal, equal to minus one, then make the front equal to zero.
Okay, we add it by then make the rear, increase it by one + + and I tend.
At the rear, so this is a rate that we are going to make, so I tunes.
Is the array that we have created called out the OK so array
array at three years at index, three year equal to element.
So you guys how the algorithms and how that logic behind adding items into the Q Works print and an
inserted inserted and we display the element value.
OK.
This is how we in Q, how we add elements that they're cute.
Now let's remove items from the Q, removing items from the Q how to do that?
It is as Dec, so it would be a returning type of this method of type and and we put the deck.
It is known as Dec, OK.
It's not the Q, and they're meant to create a variable element.
And we check if is empty.
If the queue is empty, then don't do anything because it is an empty, so suspended print and Q queue
is empty.
Return minus one.
OK.
Because and anything else, it will create element equal to that.
Are they at index feront?
Because we need to remove and we deck from the queue at the index front, OK, and not the index rate,
because we need the first element that enters the queue.
We need to remove it from greater than or equal to the rear, then from equal to minus one.
This is if it is from to greater than or equal to rear and rear, equal to minus one setting the values
that
the queue has only one element, so set the queue after deletion.
OK.
Else we have many elements of system thought out that could end, and we are removing and deleting deleted,
deleted.
What is the index?
This
plus plus element?
OK.
And return the alignment.
This is how we remove elements from the queue.
You see, guys, it's very important.
Now this is.
The ALS for ALS.
And if and else front, I need to cut this and paste them here, and I will increase the front by one.
OK.
This is what we have.
Right then, because it will need a return vet statement, and this is that returning statement or responding
to it.
OK.
So this is for the here.
And in that now let's create a method called display that display elements of that cue.
So because of time before this play,
and we start by creating a counter fly that will be used for that loop, or I can not to create that,
I can create it directly in the loop if it empty so that there is the cue and the system to doubt the
print and empty,
empty cue
health system that out the print and front.
Strong index,
the strength of going system odds are just making adjustment for the for the printing, current and
items,
and we start by for it and I equal to front, I think less than or equal to research I plus plus then
what we do is we print out I thin.
Everyday at index, a class space, and since then that the brand and it it through the year index,
it's good notation that it can make
the 30 years different and the whole right.
OK, now let's test our our program that we have created.
This is is full, OK?
We have created is full.
Not everyone.
OK,
that's that's our program.
So public static void main and string args.
We create.
Q.
Q equal to New Q, this is the constructor of the Q, and we should specify.
How many, how many items we should make in the queue?
Of course, if we go to the queue to enter the perimeter and size, I will create a queue of five elements.
OK, so.
Q dirt in Q one Q dirt in Q
in Q two.
Q, thank you.
Three.
Q Do it in Q four and Q talked HQ
Q five, OK, if we end up displaying here error.
Of full queue, so if we try to add queue in queue six, we have created a queue of five elements and
we have added them, so we try to add one another queue.
We need to get we we will get that error message now queued back.
So queue, let me display first.
The queue cured the display or display
queue thought.
This plane
and here after the cue or deck, cue the deck, we remove the first one and then we will display the
list, so we'll display the list before removing and the list after removing.
Let's run and see.
Here we go.
We start, OK, this is that for the stack, sorry.
Let me around this you.
OK, here we go.
We have inserted one, two, three, four and five when we tried to insert six, it will display for
us an error.
Cue is for now when we try to print this stack, that is sort of the cue.
The front index would be zero items.
One, two, three, four and five rear end is four and delete.
That is one.
OK.
So when we delete it, when we deck, we display that here and this now becomes four.
And that deleted is one because it is the first element that it is insert front element index one item
two, three, four and five rear.
And this is four.
OK.
So.
This is how we can make how we display that deck.
And the interview and how we work with that, Q, It's very simple.
And we are going to increase the complexity of these programs and make them more complex.
OK.
By the way, all of these methods are like in Cuba and there are of all of one gay, all of one complex,
except that display because the display is using a loop that go through all the elements.
So it is of depending on the number of the data that it is inserted into Q and Q here is of one.
OK, except the display.